솵 솵
렌트도 있고, 술도 사야하고
That there's rent,
drinking money,
트럭에 할부금도 있을지도 모르지
maybe even a down payment
on a truck.
저게 진짜 월척이지
Now, that's a catch.
저건 문제야, 데일
That's trouble, Dale.
에이미랑 엮이는 것보다
나은 일들이 훨씬 많다고
You know better
than to mess with Amy.
안녕, 메이시
Hey, Macey...
"안녕, 메이시" 라니!
Don't "Hey, Macey" me.
- 네가 얘랑 같이 잠 잔 놈이냐?
- 뭐? 아냐
You the one sleeping with her?
What? No.
내 타입도 아닌걸
맞지 제시?
She ain't even my type.
Ain't that right, Jesse?
그 새우들처럼 네 머리를
Oh, I'll pop your head off
톡 터트려주겠어
내 말 알아듣겠냐?
just like one of them shrimp.
Do you hear me?
나한테 더 할말 없냐
What do you got
to say for yourself,
이 나쁜 새끼야?
you sorry son of a bitch, huh?!
다리...
Leg.
워
Ooh.
솵 Boom, boom, boom, boom 솵
솵 Bang, bang, bang, bang 솵
솵 How, how, how, how 솵
솵 Hey, hey 솵
New Orleans 1x01 솵
Musician Heal Thyself
Original Air Date on September 23, 2014
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
솵 You gotta come on. 솵
크레센트 도시의 밤문화에
아직 적응이 안됐나, 브로디?
(뉴올리언즈는 초승달 모양의 지형때문에 crescent city라 불림)
Haven't gotten used to the
Crescent City nightlife, Brody?
제가 사는 지역이 문제예요
It's my living situation.
브로드무어에 방 두개짜리인데
Short-term lease
in a double in Broadmoor.
매일 밤 똑같은 일이 벌어지죠
술에 취한 대학생들이랑
Every night the same thing:
wasted college students
동네에 애들이 폭죽을 터트리고 놀죠
and neighborhood kids
lighting firecrackers.
그거 폭죽 아닌건 알지?
You know those
aren't firecrackers.
좀 긍정적으로 생각한거예요
I was trying
to be optimistic.
오, 누가 어젯밤에 신나게
파티하고 놀았나보죠?
Oh, someone party hard
last night?
이웃이 시끄럽게 굴었대
Noisy neighbors.
아, 그냥 우리 신입을
좀 못살게 군거예요
Oh, I'm just
hazing her.
브로디가 어디 나가지
않는건 안다니까요
I know Brody
doesn't go out.
나가서 놀긴 한다고요
I go out.
I mean, maybe not
그냥, 근사한 저녁먹으러 나갔다가
허리케인을 만나는게 싫을 뿐이죠
to the places where fine dining
meets hurricanes,
나가서 놀긴 해요
but I do go out.
아, 그럼, 그러시겠죠, 브로디양
Yeah, sure,
you do, Brody.
좋아, 크리스토퍼
이번엔 뭔가?
All right, Christopher,
what we got?
구두가 최근에 보급되고 있는 해군의 것이니
Boot is current Navy issue,
so we're operating
다리도 그렇다는 전제 하에 착수했습니다
on the assumption
the leg is as well.
드웨인, 크리스토퍼
좋은 아침이군요
Dwayne. Christopher.
Morning.
브로디 요원, 그쪽은 피곤해보이는군요
Agent Brody,
you look tired.
그만한 가치가 있었길 바래요
I hope it was
worth it.
시끄러운 애들에, 총소리였어요
절대 가치는 없죠
Loud kids. Gunshots.
Not worth it.
이봐, 걱정 마 브로디, 이제부터는
Hey, don't sweat it, Brody--
from now on,
내가 네 개인 부동산 업체처럼 일해줄테니까
I'm gonna act
as your personal rental agent.
내 여동생을 위해 한 것처럼 말이야
Just like I did
with my sister.
네가 진짜 좋아할만한 집을 찾아주지
Find you a place
you're gonna love.
오늘의 월척의...
Where we at
with I.D.'ing the...
신원을 조회하는건
어떻게 되어가나요, 로레타?
catch of the day, Loretta?
DNA 조사는 시간이 좀 걸릴꺼예요
DNA'll take time.
Unfortunately,
불행하게도 이 다리에서는
딱히 특별한 특징을...
there's no identifying
characteristics other than...
피해자가 흑인이라는걸 제외하곤
찾을 수가 없으니까요
...the victim's most
likely African-American.
시체의 부패의 상태를 보아하니
Based on the
decomp, I'd say
적어도 1주일동안은
물 속에 있었던 것 같군요
the leg's been in the
water at least a week.
악어가 공격한건 아닐까요?
Gator attack?
근육의 절단면이 너무 깔끔해요
Muscle cut's too clean.
보트 사고는요?
Boating accident?
화가 난 상어라던지?
Angry shark?
엄청 큰 오징어는 어때?
Rabid squid?
지옥에서 온 변종 불가사리라던가?
Mutant starfish from hell?
분위기 좀 띄워보라고
Just trying to keep it light.
뼈에 남은 자국에 의하면
Based on the marks on the bones,
프로펠러의 자국이나
I'd say it's inconsistent
with a propeller
변종 불가사리일 수도 있지만...
or a mutant starfish, but...
제 생각엔 하나의 칼날이 쓰인 것 같네요
I think it's a single blade.
부검을 해봐야 확실하겠지만요
Have to autopsy to make sure.
좋아, 크리스토퍼
All right, Christopher,
우리 새로 온 중서지방 똘똘이를
take our recent
Midwestern transplant
해안경비대에 소개시켜주고
and introduce her
to the Coast Guard,
그들도 수색에 동참하게 해
get them to help
in the search.
남은 조각들을 찾아보자고
Let's find the rest of him.
알았습니다, 대장
You got it, King.
- 리 경감님
- 프라이드
Captain Lee.
Pride.
제 검보의 맛을 잊을 수 가
없으신 모양이군요?
(Gumbo : 뉴올리언즈의 대표적인 음식 중 하나)
Just couldn't stay
away from my gumbo, could you?
아, 나도 내가 맛좋은 음식을 보려고 여기 온거라면 좋겠네
Oh, how I wish I were here for
a little culinary inspiration.
자네 부하가 날 들여보내줬는데
큰 문제가 안되길 바라네
Hope you don't mind--
your guard let me in.
문제 없습니다
No problem.
봐, 내가 이걸 어떻게
말해야될지 모르겠는데
Look, I don't know
how to say this,
네가 봐주던 그 애 말이야
but the kid you mentored,
켈빈 파크스 2등 상사있지
Petty Officer 2nd Class
Calvin Parks,
지금 말도 안하고 쉬고 있다네
he's unauthorized absence.
정말요?
You sure?
그 녀석 상관이 말하길
몇 일동안 본적이 없다더군
His OIC hasn't heard from
him for a couple of days.
- 너한테 연락이 갔었나 해서 말이야
- 몇일이요?
I was hoping he contacted you.
Couple of days?
그 녀석이 네가 자기한테
얼마나 큰 도움이 됐는지
He told me himself just
how much you helped him out
나한테 말한적이 있었는데
by steering him
towards the Navy.
그 녀석같은 과거를 가지고 있는 사람을
Not many people
would help a boy
도와주는건 쉽지 않지
escape a past like his.
뭐, 네, 켈빈이라면 스스로
자신의 길을 찾았을 겁니다
Yeah, well, Calvin
would have found his own way.
전 그냥 그걸 살짝 밀어준거죠
I just gave him a little push.
뭐, 그래, 자랑스러워해야겠네
Yeah, well,
you should be proud of him.
그 녀석 첫날부터 선원일을
빼먹었으니까 말이야
That kid's been a squared-away
sailor since day one.
아마 예쁜 여자라도 찾아서
정신이 없는거겠지
He probably just found
some young lady to distract him.
하지만 만약 그렇다면
But if that's the case,
그 녀석은 벌을 받게 될꺼야
he will be facing
disciplinary action.
연락이 오게되면
Give me a call
나한테 말좀 해주게, 알았나?
if you hear from him, will you?
네, 알았습니다
Yeah. I will.
다시 봐서 좋군, 프라이드
Good to see you, Pride.
로레타, 이상한 부탁 하나만 하자
Loretta.
I have a strange request.
지금 제 부검실에 놓여져있는
모르는 사람의 발보다는 낫겠죠
Not as strange as a boot
with a leg on my autopsy table.
피해자의 발 사이즈를
Could you use the size
of a victim's foot
피해자 묘사 하는데 쓸 수 있나?
as a basis
for a general description?
안녕하세요, 프라이드
Hey, Pride.
아니면 "드웨인" 이라고 불러드릴까요?
Or should I say "Dwayne"?
제 생각에는 제가
당신을 드웨인이라고
I thought it might be
more appropriate for me
부르는 게 더 나을것 같아요
to start calling you Dwayne,
what with us
여테까지 NCIS에서
자문을 해 온걸 생각하면요
consulting for NCIS
all these years.
결론적으로, 서로 상대방의 이름을
부르는건 친숙하다는 뜻이니까요
After all, the use of first
names is a sign of familiarity,
그리고 서로의 성을 부르는건
and we're a far cry from when
the surname was an indication
- 전문적인...
- 세바스찬
of a man's trade, so...
Sebastian.
일단은 프라이드로 해두죠
I'll stick
with Pride, for now.
뭐, 어, 아무튼, 실제
시체를 찾지 못했을 경우에
Yeah. Uh, anyway,
I started a computer simulation
피해자의 키, 몸무게, 나이를 대충
to estimate height,
weight and age of the deceased
컴퓨터 시뮬레이션을 돌려봤는데요
in case the body
was never found.
그럼 뭐 하나 물어보자
Then let me ask you...
피해자가...
could it be a...
23살 아프리카계 미국인일 가능성이 있나?
23-year-old African-American?
189센치에.. 몸무게는 대략 99키로 에서
Six, three; maybe 220 or...
102키로 정도?
225 pounds?
가능성이 있죠
이 경우와 거의 비슷하네요
It's possible, even likely.
이름이랑 사진을 보내주도록 하지
I'll send you
a name and a photo.
좋았어
Yeah, baby.
5분만 쉽시다, 알았죠?
Let's take
a quick five, all right?
드웨인! 내 친구!
Dwayne! My man!
파파 파크스
Papa Parks.
- 정말 연주 잘하던데
- 앞자리에 앉을래?
You sounded good.
You want to sit in next set?
혹시... 켈빈한테 소식 들은거 있나?
Have you... have you heard
from Calvin lately?
어, 적어도 몇주는 됬지
Uh, it's been at least
a couple weeks.
저녁 먹으러 오거든, 왜?
He'd come over for supper. Why?
내가 켈빈을 정말 아끼는거 알지?
You know I think
the world of Calvin.
내 피같은 자식같은 존재라고 생각하는거
He's like my blood,
the son I never had.
드웨인...
Dwayne...
말해봐
just tell me.
뭔가가...
Something...
켈빈에게 뭔가 나쁜일이
일어났을지도 몰라...
might have happened to Calvin,
something bad.
- 하지만 확실하진 않은거지?
- 그래
But you're not sure?
Mm-mm.
확실하진 않아
I'm not sure.
파파, 다시 오셔야해요
Papa, we're up again.
내가 인생을 살면서
사랑한게 딱 두가지인데
Only two things
I ever loved in this life:
켈빈과 재즈였어
Calvin and jazz.
그 중 하나를 꽉 잡고
Gonna hold on tight
to one...
다른 하나를 잃어버리지 않았길 빌어야지
and pray I haven't
lost the other.
좋아, 파파!
All right, Papa!
"시체 찾았음, 켈빈 파크스"
프라이드, 거기 있나?
Yo, Pride, you here?
부엌에
Kitchen.
와! 냄새 정말 좋네요!
Wow! Smells good!
좋은 아침이예요, 대장
Morning, King.
언제 들어오셨어요?
What time you get in?
뭐, 그 말대로라면 내가 이곳을
떠났었다는 소리잖아
Well, that assumes I left.
내가 윗층에 사는거 알면서 그러나
You know I've been
staying upstairs.
달걀 크레올에
Eggs Creole...
엔두일 소세지에
레몰라드 소스야
andouille sausage
and remoulade sauce.
좋네요
Nice.
접시들 들고 켈빈 파크스의 수사가
Grab plates,
and tell me where we are
어떻게 되어가는지 말해봐
with the Calvin Parks
investigation.
어젯밤 그의 침실을
뒤져보긴 했습니다만
So, last night we went down
and searched his rack.
이상한건 하나도 없었습니다
Nothing out
of the ordinary,
개인용 노트북을 찾긴 했는데요
but we did recover
a personal laptop.
- 비밀번호가 걸려있나?
- 그걸 풀 수 있도록
Password-protected?
Which we've sent out
연구소에 보냈고, 그 동안에 저희는
to get a work-around.
Meantime, we thought
그가 만나고 다니던 사람들을
한번 조사해보려고요
we'd canvass
his day-to-day contacts.
군수 지원 센터에 속해있더군요
He was assigned to the pier-side
Fleet Logistics Center.
부두에서 물건을 싣는 일을 했습니다
He worked the wharfs,
loading inventory,
음식이나 장비 같은 것들 말이죠
food and equip.
좋아, 너희 둘은 부두를 맡고
Okay, you two
take the wharfs.
나는 웨이드 선생한테 가서
법의학쪽은 어떤지 보도록 하지
I'll go see
Doc Wade about forensics.
잠시 자리좀 비워줄래?
Let me talk
to him for a second.
네
Yep.
그냥 가서...
Just gonna go...
전화기 좀... 찾아올께요
grab my... phone.
프라이드, 영안실은
제가 가 드릴 수도 있어요
Pride, I can take the morgue,
if you like.
개인적으로 연루되어 있으시니까...
I thought since... you
were personally involved,
이번 건은 가고 싶지
않으실 수도 있잖아요
you might want
to take a pass on this one.
파파랑은 거의 한세기동안 친구였다고
Got a decade-old
friendship with Papa.
내가 그냥 손놓고 있을 것 같나?
You think I'm just
gonna sit on my hands?
저희가 찾는 것들이
And if the things
we uncover
듣고 싶지 않으신 거라면요?
are things you and he
don't want to hear?
마주할건 마주해야지
We face what
we got to face.
브로디를 데려가
Take Brody,
배우라고
learn things.
뭐하고 있는거야?
What the hell
you waiting for?
뭐, 아침 주신다면서요?
Well, you did offer breakfast.
그럼 싸갈께요
We'll take it to go.
당신이 부두 노동자 관리인이고
You're the longshoremen
supervisor-- and that's...
- 그게 민간 직업이라고요?
- 네, 계약직이죠
a civilian position?
Contractor, yeah.
부두는 많은 사람들에게
다용도로 사용되거든요...
Port is zoned mixed-use,
so... we have various clients,
그 중에는 해군도 있고요
which include the Navy.
그리고 파크스 상사를 관리하셨고요?
And you oversaw
Petty Officer Parks?
칼이요
Cal.
네, 좋은 아이였죠
Yeah. Good kid.
항상 제시간에 도착하고
Great kid. On time.
예의바르고, 열심히 일했어요
Polite. Hard-working.
더는 없나요?
Something more?
나쁜 말은 하고 싶지 않은데요
I don't want to speak
ill, you know?
하지만... 나쁜 버릇이라는게
쉽게 죽지는 않는 모양이더라고요
But... maybe old
habits die hard.
이봐!
Hey!
세상에 대체 둘이서
What in the
kingdom of God
지금 뭘 하고 있는거야? 응?
are you two doing? Huh?
니콜스 지사 길 부두로 가
Get over to Governor
Nicholls Street Wharf,
거기서 짐이나 옮겨!
off-load those pallets.
덜 떨어진 애들은
늘 돌봐줘야 하거든요
Got to keep an eye
on the chuckleheads.
"나쁜 버릇" 이라고 말씀하셨었는데요
You said, uh,
something about "old habits."
네, 뭐
Yeah, just,
음, 켈빈과 같은 근무시간 대의
애들한테 들은 예기인데
uh... just heard talk from
guys on Calvin's shift.
무슨 슬럼가 차량에
근처 패거리랑 함께
They said that they saw
him leave in a lowrider
떠나는걸 봤다고 하더군요
with some local bangers.
패거리는 갱이라는 소리야
Bangers are gang members.
제가 온 곳이 디트로이트의
심문하는 쪽이에요
My background is
in interrogation,
out of Detroit.
저도 무슨 뜻인지 알아요, 고마워요
I know the lingo. Thanks.
누구 자세하게 얼굴을
본 사람은 없나요? 이...
Anyone get a look
at any of these...
"패거리"들이요
bangers?
제가 말했듯이
Like I said,
제가 직접 본 건 아니지만
I wasn't there to see this,
애들이 말하길
but... the guys said
딱히 친절하게 생기진 않았다고 하더라고요
that, uh, they didn't
look too friendly.
Body was discovered
시체는 11번 고속도로의 근처에 있는
얕은 무덤에서 플라스틱에 쌓인체로 발견됬어요
wrapped in plastic
in a shallow grave
near Highway 11.
뉴올리언즈의 동쪽이죠
New Orleans East.
11번 대로는 폰체트레인 호수로 흘러가는
Highway 11 is near
the Irish Bayou.
아이리시 지류의 옆에 있는 길이잖아
That channels
into Lake Pontchartrain.
다리를 걸프에서 건졌고 말이야
The leg was scooped up
in the Gulf.
이게 대체 무슨 소리야?
How does that make sense?
아직 무기가 뭔지도 몰라요
I don't even know
what the weapon is yet,
하지만 죽기 직전의 경과를 보면
but the severing is
antemortem, which means
그가 살아있는 상태에서 다리가
분리 되었다는 걸 알 수 있었어요
it was disassociated
while he was still alive.
그러니까, 걸프로 흘러가는
물 근처에서 켈빈을 죽여놓고
So, they kill him near a body
of water that flows to the Gulf.
그 자리에서 다리는
버리고, 시체 자체는
The-the leg gets dumped there,
left behind,
잘 싸서 옮기고, 묻어줬다고?
and the body is wrapped,
moved and buried?
양쪽 손의 관절에
We have significant contusions
심각한 타박상이 있었어요
on the knuckles
of both hands.
싸웠다는건가?
So, a fight?
뭐, 방어하다 생긴 상처지만요
Well, it's defense wounds.
그리고 결과가 나빴다고 해도
And although the
outcome was grievous,
켈빈이 몇방 먹여주긴 했어요
Calvin got some
good licks in.
The basic theory.
간단한 이론이예요
세바스찬이 시뮬레이션을 돌려봤어요
Sebastian did
the simulation.
살인자가 켈빈한테 나타났고
논쟁이 있었겠죠
The killer came upon Calvin,
there was an altercation.
살인자는 크고
날카로운 물체가 있었죠
The killer had
a large, sharp object.
제 생각에는 도끼같아요
Think Axe.
다리를 가격한 공격이 있었고
There was the attack
that severed the limb, and...
켈빈은 출혈사했군
Calvin bled out.
- 드웨인...
- 그냥 계속 말해줘, 로레타, 부탁해
Dwayne...
Just keep talking, Loretta. Please.
알았어요
Okay.
이런게 옷에 껴 있었어요
We found this caught up
in the clothing.
두번째 앞니죠
It's a second bicuspid,
아마 오른쪽일꺼예요
probably on the right side.
그리고 켈빈의 이빨은 절대 아니고요
It's definitely not Calvin's,
왜냐하면 켈빈은
이빨이 전부 있거든요
'cause he's still
sporting a full set.
그러니까, 살인자는 이빨이 없다는거네
So, whoever killed him
is missing a tooth.
DNA는 빼봤어?
Pull DNA?
아직 근처 범죄자 데이터베이스에서 검색중이예요
Still running it through
the local criminal database.
그리고 또 보셔야 될 게 있어요
There's something else
I think you should see.
이거 "델타 크루"의 문신이죠?
That's Delta Crew, right?
칼은 9번지의 아래쪽에서 자랐지
Cal grew up in the Lower Ninth.
12살에 갱에 들어가게 되었었어
Got pulled into the gangs
by the time he was 12.
뭐, 저 피부반응에 의하면
저 문신은 새거예요
Well, based on that irritation,
that tat's new.
새로운 잉크라고?
Fresh ink?
굉장히 최근의 것이죠
Very.
바이스에 있을때 봤어요
I saw it when I was in vice.
갱들이 옛날 맴버들에게
다시 들어오라고 해놓고
Gangs get their former members
to recommit.
죽여버리는거죠
Then they kill 'em.
어린 녀석들에게
도망치는건 선택지가 아니라는걸
It's an effective way
to show the kids
보여줄 수 있는 최고의 방법이예요
that getting out
is not an option.
"죽여서 괴롭히기" 라고도 불리죠
It's called "dead hazing."
"사디스트" 같다고도 할 수 있죠
It's called "sadistic."
만약 델타 크루 녀석들이
하지 않았다면?
What if the Delta Crew
didn't do it themselves?
그럼 113녀석들이겠네요
Well, it'd be the 1-1-3s.
델타 크루와 113 녀석들은
몇년동안 전쟁을 치루고 있거든요
Delta Crew and 1-1-3
have been at war for years.
뉴올리언스의 "블러드" 와
"크립스" 같은 녀석들이지
That's New Orleans's answer
to the Bloods and Crips.
죄송해요, "블러드" 와 "크립스"라고요?
(미국의 대표적 갱단들)
I'm sorry. The
Bloods and Crips?
그... 그들이 누구죠?
Who-who are they exactly?
델타 크루와 113 녀석들의
영토는 바로 옆에 붙어있어요
Delta Crew and 1-1-3 territories
are right next to each other.
사우스 갈베즈 길이 그 경계선이죠
South Galvez Street's
the border.
어느 쪽 갱단을 더 잘 아나?
Which gang do you know best?
- 델타 크루요
- 좋아
Delta Crew.
All right.
그쪽으로 가보고, 나는 브로디에게
113 녀석들의 매력을 느끼게 해줄께
Take them. I'll introduce Brody
to the charms of the 1-1-3s.
가자고
Let's go.
좋아요, 아파트 후보들이예요
All right, potential
new apartments.
2725 프리타니아요?
2725 Prytania?
거기 비싸잖아
That's Uptown.
600불짜리 유모차에
How do you feel
about $600 strollers
모든 걸 유기농으로 먹을래?
and organic everything?
좋아요, 3115 로얄은요?
Okay, 3115 Royal.
물 근처에
The Bywater.
턱수염에 안경테는 두껍고
기어달린 자전저에...
Neck beards, thick-rimmed
glasses, fixed-gear bikes.
여기선 큰 선택이야, 브로디
It's a big choice here, Brody.
어디서 사는지가
곧 네가 누군지 말한다고
Where you live
says everything.
라살은 프랑스 거리에서 있는걸 좋아해
Lasalle lives
in the French Quarter
왜냐하면 모든것의 중심이
되는 것을 좋아하거든
'cause he loves being
in the middle of it all.
내 아내와 나는... 아래쪽에 있는데
My wife and I--
we're in the Lower Garden,
미국 전역에서 최고의 요리사들이
'cause it's walking distance
걸어다닐 수 있는
거리에 있기 때문이지
from some of the best chefs
in America.
말해봐
Speak.
그냥 아내분만 아래쪽에 있고
Just looks like your
wife's in the Lower Garden.
대장은 사무실에서 사는 것처럼 보이는데요?
You're in the office.
내가 말하고자 하는 건...
All I'm saying--
어디다가 발을 디디는지가
네가 누군지 알려준다는거야
where you lay your head
in this city defines you.
좋아요, 그럼 조용하게
잠을 자고 싶다면
Okay, so where do I go
대체 어디로 가는게 좋을까요?
if I want to be defined
by a full night's sleep?
뭐, 조용하긴 하잖아
Well, it's quiet.
켈빈?
Calvin?
그 새끼 GI 조 놀이 한다고
나간 뒤로 본 적 없는데
I ain't seen that joker
since he went to go play GI Joe.
GI 조가 곧 군대지
Well, GI Joe
is the Army.
- 나한테는 다 같은데
- 그래서 지금 왜 켈빈이
All the same to me.
So, you can't
새로운 델타 크루 문신을 한채로
죽었는지 설명 불가능하다는거야?
explain how we found him
with a fresh Delta Crew tat?
모르겠네
Nah.
누가 켈빈을 죽인지 가설이라도 있나?
You got any theories
on who did Calvin?
- 천천히 가자고, 친구
- 그냥 말하는 것 뿐이야
Slow down, my man.
I'm just saying.
지금이든 나중이든...
델타가 죽었다는건
A dead Delta--
current or former--
곧 뭘 뜻하겠어?
only means one thing, right?
113 녀석들이야
1-1-3s.
슬슬 가보는게 좋을거같은데
Think it's time for you to go.
그냥 여기 앉아서
시원한 음료수나 마저 끝내고
Think I'll sit here and finish
my cold drink, thank you.
준비가 되면 나갈껀데
Leave when I get ready.
이봐 나오미
Hey, Naomi.
다이어트 오렌지 좀 줘
Give me a diet orange.
그거 때문에 내가
여기 있잖아, 자기
That's what I'm
here for, baby.
켈빈이라는 녀석은 들은적도 없는데요
Man, I ain't never heard
of no Calvin.
들어본 적 있냐고 물어본 거 아니야
Didn't ask you
if you heard of him.
왜 죽었냐고 물어본거지
Asked why he's dead.
눈 정말 예쁘네
You got some pretty,
pretty eyes.
합기도에 검은띠도 있어요
I've also got
a black belt in Aikido.
델다 크루가 자기 녀석들을 죽인게
You know, this wouldn't
be the first time
이번이 처음이 아닌거 아시죠?
Delta Crew done killed one
of their own, right?
네 이빨은 좀 어떠냐, 자식아?
How are your teeth there, Swag?
- 제 이빨이요?
- 그래
My teeth?
Yeah.
입벌리고 "아" 해봐
Open up. Give me an "ah."
아...
Ah...
전부 진짜라고요
All original.
충치도 없고요
No cavities.
하루에 두번씩 치실을 쓴다니까요
I even floss twice a day.
엎드려!
Cover!
전부 엎드려!
Get down!
Everybody get down!
엎드려!
Get down.
어젯밤 막 총격사건이 일어났던
We're reporting
from the West Bank
웨스트 뱅크에서 보도드리고 있습니다
where violence erupted
on the streets
지역의 두 가장 악명높은
of New Orleans last night,
the latest chapter
갱단의 전쟁의
in an ongoing war
가장 최근 소식을 들고 말이죠
between two of the area's
most notorious gangs...
델타 크루는 113의 짓이라고 하고
113은 델다 크루의 짓이라고 하니
Delta Crew blame 1-1-3, and
1-1-3 put it on Delta Crew.
함정 인것 같네요
Feels like a setup.
누가 한건진 모르겠지만
Just can't tell
from which side.
아, 좋은 아침일세, 드웨인
Ah, morning, Dwayne.
시의원님
Councilman.
문잠구는걸 기억했어야되는데
Got to remember
to lock the door.
- 이것좀...
- 데워드리죠
Might need a...
Warm-up.
저도 그럴 생각이였거든요
I was thinking the same.
가족은 좀 어떤가, 드웨인?
Mm. So, how's the family,
Dwayne?
린다는 잘 있고?
Linda well?
뭘 해드릴까요, 헤밀턴씨
What can I do for you, Hamilton?
뭐, 굳이 물어야하나?
What, you need to ask?
내 말은, 지금 밖에 갱단끼리
싸움이 일어나고 있는데
I mean, there's a gang war
going on out there,
그 놈들을 휘휘 젓고 있는건
and I hear that
your people are the ones
그쪽이라고 들어서 말이야
who've been stirring up the pot.
저희는 수사를 하고 있었습니다
We're conducting
an investigation.
뭐, 나는 긴급 반-갱단을 이끌고 있어서 말이야
Well, I'm organizing an
emergency anti-gang task force.
FBI, NOPD, 모두 도와주고 있는데
FBI, NOPD,
everybody's on board.
뭐, 혹시... NCIS도 참석하고 싶은지
And I was... well, I was hoping
궁금해서 말이야
that NCIS might, uh...
want to join up, too.
- 저희가 도와드릴 수 있는 한에서 말이죠
- 뭐, 좋아
We'll help any way we can.
Well, good.
이름좀 줘봐
Give me some names.
용의자 좀 줄여보자고
Let my people
start rounding up suspects.
보세요...
Look, you...
제가 이곳 커뮤니티를
어떻게 생각하는지 아시잖아요
you know how I feel
about this community.
갱을 좋아하는 사람들은 없죠. 하지만
저희는 아직 켈빈 파크스의
No one has less love for
the gangs, but we haven't
살인에 대해서 그들이 연관되었었는지도
아직 모른단 말입니다
determined that they had a
hand in Calvin Parks' murder.
뭐, 그걸 알려면
얼마나 더 오래 걸릴 것 같나?
Well, how long is it gonna be
before you determine something?
왜냐하면 사람들은 거리가
더 깨끗하길 바라고 있거든
'Cause people want
their streets cleaned up,
그리고 가끔은, 그냥
보이는게 전부이기도 하지
and sometimes,
all that matters is appearances.
제가 멍청했네요, 정말 중요한건
정의인 줄 알았는데 말이죠
Silly me, I thought
what mattered was justice.
알았네
Okay.
축복된 하루 보내라고
You have a blessed day.
정치쪽으로는 절대로 가지 마, 크리스토퍼
Don't ever go into
politics, Christopher.
순식간에, 선과 악의 정의가 얼마나 더 많은
표를 얻는지가 되어버리니까 말이야
All of a sudden, your definition
of good and evil becomes defined
by how many votes it gets you.
직감은 믿지만...
I trust your instincts, but...
"갱단이 연루가 된건지는 모르겠다" 라고요?
"We hadn't determined
the gangs are involved yet"?
앞뒤가 안맞잖아
Something doesn't
make sense.
113 녀석들이 했다면
델타 크루 녀석들이
If the 1-1-3s did it,
they'd be expecting
복수할 것을 대비했어야 했는데
그렇지 않았잖아
the Delta Crew to retaliate,
and they weren't.
만약 델타 크루가 했다면
If the Delta Crew did it...
왜 지나가면서 총을 쐈겠어?
then why the drive-by?
그리고, 그냥... 켈빈이 그 세계로
And I... I just
can't believe
다시 발을 들여놓았다는걸 믿을수가 없네
Calvin went back
into that world.
믿을 수가 없는건가요?
믿기 싫은건가요?
You can't, or you
don't want to?
둘 다 조금씩이라면 어떨까
How about a little of both?
어디에 들어있나?
Which one's he in?
맨 위 오른쪽에요
Top right.
대신 열어드릴까요?
Want me to open it up for you?
갑자기 다시 되살아나서
You think
he'll reanimate
뭘 할 작정이였는지
설명해줄거라고 생각해?
and explain what the
hell he was up to?
아뇨
No.
그럼 무슨 의미가 있나?
Then what's the point?
켈빈은 어떻게 만나셨어요?
파파를 통해서요?
How'd you meet Calvin?
Through Papa?
아니, 아니... 켈빈은...
No. No, I...
켈빈을 처음 만난건 그 녀석이
내 집을 털려고 할때였어
I met Calvin when he was trying
to rob my house.
린다랑 내가 집에 돌아왔는데
Linda and I came home.
옆 창문이 깨져있고
거실에서 내 카메라를
Side window was broken,
there's this skinny kid
만지작 거리고 있는
얇상한 녀석이 있는거야
in the parlor making off
with my camera.
그래서 뒷덜미를 잡아채서
I grabbed his punk ass,
그 녀석을 벽에 몰아세우고
잡아넣으려고
threw him against the wall,
and in the time it took
그 녀석을 돌려세운...
to turn him...
그 순간...
over to someone...
그 녀석 안에서 뭔가를 봤어
I saw something in him.
그리고, 알잖아, 그냥...
And, you know,
it just...
다시 그 세계로 돌아갔다고
생각을 하니까 그냥...
it kills me to think that
he went back into that world.
빠져나오는건 정말 힘들죠
Getting out is hard, isn't it?
하지만 바꾸려고 했잖아요
But he was trying to change.
우린 우리가 아는 것에
매달리 곤 하지
We're attached to what we know.
그렇죠
Yeah.
상담해줘서 고마워, 로레타
I appreciate your counsel,
Loretta.
상담해주셔서 고마워요, 드웨인
And I yours, Dwayne.
두분만 있게 해드리죠
I'll leave you alone with him.
절 보고 싶으시다고요
You wanted to see me?
그래, 기술자가 노트북의
비밀번호를 알아냈는데
Yeah, tech got
around the password.
별건 없네
There's not much here,
그냥 보통 SNS 사이트로 가득하고
but basic social media sites
fill his browser history.
셰레브 포트에 있는
여자에게 보낸 편지 빼고는
E-mails sent to a girl
in Shreveport.
갱 활동에서 멀어지거나 가까워질만한
단서는 하나도 없어
Nothing that really leads to
or away from gang involvement.
아, 그래서 건진게 아무것도 없다고요?
Oh, so nothing helpful.
뭐, 아무것도 없는건 아니지
Well, not nothing.
자기한테 이메일을 보냈는데
He sent an e-mail to himself
NMCI 계정에서
자기 개인 계정으로 말이야
from his NMCI account
to his personal account.
제목은 없는데, 안에는
큰 숫자들이 있었어
No subject. But inside,
there's a bunch of numbers.
봐, 큰 숫자지
Look. Big numbers.
8749 이랑 9449도 있고
더 작은 것도 있어
8749 and 9449.
Some smaller.
22.3이랑 12.6도 있네
22.3 and 12.6.
그리고 큰 숫자는 그냥 반복돼
The big numbers
keep repeating.
켈빈은 부두에서 일하고 있었죠
So, he was working the wharfs.
이 숫자들은 시간은 아닌데요
These aren't times.
배 숫자나, 좌표도 아니야
Not ship numbers
or coordinates.
3493이라
3493.
저 이 숫자 알아요
I know that number.
대체 이게 뭔데?
What in the Sam Hill
does that mean?
제가 크로스워드 퍼즐
어떻게 푸는지 아시죠
You know how
I do crosswords.
- 머리속으로?
- 제가 뭘 보면 바로 거기에 박혀요
In your head?
I see something, and it sticks.
3493. 분명히 제가 어디서 본 숫자예요
3493. I am telling you,
that is a number I've seen.
아주 멋지게 단장하고 왔지만
You present yourself
all buttoned up,
역시 넌 이상한 녀석이야, 브로디
but you are an
odd bird, Brody.
와줘서 고마워
Thank you for coming, dear.
어떻게 그러실 수
있는지 정말 대단해요
I love that you
can do that.
마치 뒷통수에 눈이라도
달리신것 같다니까요
Just, eyes in the
back of your head.
아니면 카메라에 비치는
네 모습이라던지 말이야
Or your reflection
in the back of my camera.
폭풍?
Thunderstorm?
뭘까요
Probably what?
다 늙어가는 세포의 뭉치라던가?
Mature stage multicell cluster.
그냥 비야, 비를 좋아하거든
It's just rain. I like rain.
누가 싫어하겠어요?
Who doesn't?
뭐, 고양이는 싫어하죠
Well, cats don't.
뱀도 싫어하고요
And snakes don't.
그리고 제 누나, 아나토니아도
And my sister Antonia, actually,
습윤을 굉장히 싫어했어요
이것도 전에...
she was a bit ombrophobic,
which I never really...
세바스찬, 문신이 어떻게
사라지게 만들 수 있을까?
Sebastian, what could make
a tattoo disappear?
이 사진들은 내가
I've taken these photos,
3시간마다 찍은건데
one every three hours.
매번 찍을때마다 문신이
See how in each shot
점점 얕아져가는게 보여?
the tattoo seems
to be getting lighter.
보통 문신은 이렇게 되지 않는다고
Typical putrefaction just
doesn't account for this.
- 샘플을 가져가도 될까요?
- 그래
Mind if I take a sample?
Mm-hmm.
이런거랑 비슷한 사건을
워싱턴에서 본 적이 있을것 같은데
I think I remember a similar
case out of Washington,
문신을 이용해서 사망시간을
where they used the tattoo
to determine
추론했던거 말이야
time of death.
멜라드 박사가 검시관이였군
And Dr. Mallard was the coroner.
다시 이야기할 수 있는
좋은 기회가 되겠네
Lovely excuse to catch up.
프라이드입니다
Pride here.
네, 가도록하죠
Yeah, I'm on my way.
월터가 전화를 했어
Walter called.
연주하지 않겠다고 했다며?
Said you weren't gonna play.
15년만에 처음이군, 안그래?
First time in 15 years, huh?
그냥 닦으려고 분리를
했을땐 괜찮았는데
I took it apart to clean it
like I always do,
다시 조립할 시간이 되니...
but when it came time to
put it back together,
그냥... 안되더라고
I just... couldn't.
그렇게 됐어
I'm like that.
조각나버렸다고
In pieces.
누가 켈빈을 죽였는지는 찾았나?
You find whoever killed Calvin?
아직, 하지만 찾아낼꺼야
Not yet. But I will.
찾아낼꺼란걸 알아
I know that.
그리고
And I also know
네가 다시 연주를 한다면
that you will feel better,
조금이라도 말이야
just a little,
나아질꺼야
if you play.
그냥 계속 이런 생각이 들어
I just keep thinking...
녀석이 다시 갱과 어울렸다면
if he went back
with them gangs...
그건 내 잘못이라고 말이야
that's my fault.
내가 뭔가를 했거나
If I'd just
done something
뭔가를 안했거나
or didn't do something
뭔... 뭔가를 했어야 했거나 말이야
or-or could've done something...
연주할 수가 없어, 드웨인
I can't play, Dwayne.
다시는 연주 할 수
있을 것 같지가 않네
Doesn't feel like I ever will.
무슨 일이 일어났었는지
알아내기 전에는 말이야
Not without knowing
what happened.
코트하고 모자 챙겨
Go grab your coat and hat.
같이 좀 걷자고, 같이...
We'll take a walk. We'll...
얘기 좀 나눠보자
we'll talk.
어때?
Huh?
내가 말할껀 아무것도
없어, 오랜 친구여
I got nothing to say,
old friend.
- 안녕, 아빠
- 안녕, 얘야
Hey, Daddy.
Hey, baby.
안녕, 어, 나 지금
수업중이어서 말이야, 별 일 없어?
Hey, uh, I'm in class.
Is everything all right?
괜찮아졌어
It is.
목소리를 듣고 나니 말이야
Now that I've heard your voice.
죄송해요, 또 늦게 잤거든요
Sorry. Another late night.
개가 짖더라고요
Dogs barking.
그냥 내가 새로운 장소를
찾게 도와주면 안될까?
Why don't you let me
help you find a place?
제시는 고마워요, 정말요
I appreciate
the offer. I do.
개인적인건 없지만, 전...
Nothing personal. I just, um...
공과 사는 확실하게
선을 그어두고 싶어서요
I prefer that my work and
personal lives be kept separate.
여기선 그런건 안통한다고
That's not the way it works
around here.
우린 모두 하나의 큰 가족이야
We're all one big family.
빨리 납득 할 수록
쉬워질꺼라고
Sooner you accept that,
the easier it's gonna be.
그러는동안, 내 피의 당분이 줄어버렸네
In the meantime,
my blood sugar's getting low.
디저트나 시켜보자고
Let's order dessert.
음, 좋아요
Mmm, okay.
어디보자, 메뉴가 어디있나
Let's see. Where's
this menu at here?
여기있군
Here we go.
오, 빵푸딩은 진짜
내가 추천하는거야
Oh, I recommend
the bread pudding.
키 라임 파이
Key lime pie.
나쁠 수가 없지
Can't go wrong.
파인애플?
Pineapple?
그건 안파는거같은데
I don't think they have any.
3493.
파인애플이요
Pineapple.
정부에서 재고를 정리할때
하위 그룹을 만드는데
Government uses National Stock
Numbers which contain subgroups
숫자로 주정부 그룹이나, 주정부 물품 그룹이나
that identify Federal Supply
Groups, Federal Supply Classes,
NATO 나라 코드나
주립 물품 아이디 넘버 (NIIN)를
NATO country codes and National
Item Identification Numbers,
숫자로 매기거든요
or NIINs.
- 좀 천천히 해
- 3493은 파인애플의
Slow down.
3493 is the NIIN
주립 물품 아이디 넘버예요
이런걸 아는 이유는
for pineapple, which I know
제 전 약혼자가 이상한
과일 샐러드 성애자였거든요
because my ex-fianc챕
had a weird fruit salad fetish.
전 약혼자도 있었어?
You have an ex-fianc챕?
어쨋든 , 켈빈이 부두에서 일했었죠?
So, Calvin worked
the wharfs, right?
3493을 쓴 만큼
파인애플의 상자가 들어왔고
3493 is a number he wrote
however many times.
Pallets of pineapples.
큰 숫자들이 물품이였다면
And if the big numbers
were products,
작은 숫자들은...
then the smaller numbers
must have been...
무게겠군, 좋아
숫자로 다시 돌아가서
Were weights. All right,
let's get back to the numbers
다른 물품들이 뭐였는지 보자고
and figure out
what the other shipments were.
좋아요, 그래도 빵푸딩은 시켜도 될까요?
Okay, fine, but can we still
have some bread pudding?
당연하지
Absolutely.
내가 마지막으로 뉴올리언스에
갔던걸 기억하나, 로레타?
Do you remember the last time
I was in New Orleans, Loretta?
- 2004년 12월 25일이였지
- 그렇죠
December the 25th, 2004.
Right.
뉴올리언스에 단 한번밖에 없는
눈이 오는 날이었고 말이야
Which happened to be the only
snowfall day in New Orleans
1989년부터 내리지 않던 그 눈 말이야
since 1989.
뭐, 혹시 박사님이
그 눈의 원인이라면
Well, if you were
the cause of the snow,
다시는 오지 않으시면 좋겠군요
you're not welcome back.
다시 보니 좋군, 프라이드 요원
Good to see you, Agent Pride.
제 생각에는 박사님과 제가 방금 막
I think the good doctor and I
just figured out
왜 켈빈의 문신이 벗겨졌는지
알아낸 것 같아요
why Calvin's tattoo
was coming off.
그래, 거의 4년전에
Yes, I had a case
피해자가 죽기 바로 몇시간 전에
nearly four years ago
문신을 했던 사건을
where the tattoo was applied
한번 맡은 적이 있었지
only hours prior
to the victim's death.
결과는 문신은 피가 돌지 않아서
The result: The micropunctures
didn't have time to heal
자리를 잡지 못하고
빠져나가 버렸었어요
because the blood
couldn't congeal.
저희 생각에는 그게 켈빈한테
일어나는 것 같아요
We think that's what's going on
with Calvin.
좋아, 그래서...
All right. So...
덕키의 사건을 전제로 켈빈이 문신을 얻었던
We tried to use Ducky's case
as a baseline to approximate
시간을 추론해 보았는데
when Calvin received the tattoo,
차이가 거의 3시간정도밖에 나지 않았어요
and the difference was
approximately three hours.
죽기 전 3시간 전에 문신을 받았다고요?
He got the tattoo three hours
before he died?
아뇨
No.
이 경우에는
In this case,
피해자는 사망 한 뒤에
문신을 받은거야
the tattoo was applied
after death.
피가 아예 안통하니
잉크가 남아있을 수가 없죠
The ink won't hold because
there's no blood flow at all.
그러니까 켈빈은 델타 크루로
돌아간게 아니였군요
So Calvin wasn't back
with the Delta Crew.
살인자가 문신을 놓은거죠
Killer put the tat on.
사후에요
Posthumously.
이게 갱의 짓인것처럼 보이도록 말이죠
To make this look like part
of a gang killing.
정말 잘했어
That's good work.
그거면 4개네요
That'd be a four.
좋아, 그걸 빼고 새로운 숫자 줘봐
Okay, so subtract that
and give me the new number.
이봐!
Hey!
오, 일어나셨네
Oh, he's up.
- 밤새고 일한거야?
- 어차피 제 방에서는
- You two been up all night?
- It's not like I get
잠을 잘 수도 없는걸요
any sleep at my place anyway.
둘이 조용히 하기로 하기도 했어요
We made a point of trying
to keep it down for you.
코 고시던데요
You snore.
크게요
Loud.
안고는데
No, I don't.
이거 한번 보실래요?
Can you take a look at this?
그래서, 갱쪽이 아닌걸 전제로
So, working off
the theory
조사를
that the gang angle
isn't real, we are convinced
조사를 해 본 결과
살인은 켈빈이 부두에서 일하던 것과
관계가 있다고 결론이 났어요
that the murder had to do with
Calvin working at the wharf.
켈빈의 컴퓨터에 있던 큰 숫자는 전부
Those big numbers
in Calvin's computer,
부두에서 싣던 국제 물품 번호들이예요
they're all NIIN for different
items loaded at the port.
3493, 파인애플
3493, pineapple.
8748, 바나나
9449, 커피
8748, bananas. 9449, coffee.
모두 같은 배에서 온 것들이죠
All coming in on the same boat,
which originated
- 과테말라에서요
- 그러니까, 과테말라에서 물품의 무게를 재죠
in Guatemala.
So, in Guatemala,
the pallets are weighed, right?
그리고 배가 뉴올리언스로 오고
Then the boat sails
to New Orleans,
모든 물품들이 해군에게 넘어가죠
where all the cargo
is transferred to Navy ships.
하지만 넘어가기 전에
무게를 다시 재거든요
But before
it's put aboard, it's weighed again.
켈빈의 이메일에 있던 작은 숫자들입니다
The smaller numbers
in Calvin's e-mails,
전부 과테말라에서 왔던 무게들과
those are the difference
between the Guatemala
- 뉴올리언스에서 쟀던 무게예요
- 그러니까 물품들이
and New Orleans weights.
The pallets ended up
해군이 얻기 전에
가벼워졌다 이 말이야?
being lighter by the time
the Navy got a hold of them?
밀수로군
Smuggling.
무게의 차이로 보건데
Based on the weight
differentials,
아마 총이나 마약이 아닐까 생각됩니다
we're thinking, uh,
guns or drugs.
그래서 문제는
So the question is,
켈빈이 그걸 알아냈기 때문에
살해당한 것일까요
was Calvin murdered
because he found out about it
아니면 동참을 했다가 살해당한걸까요?
or because he was in on it?
동참을 하다니?
In on it?
컴퓨터에 있던 비밀번호나
Password
on his computer,
메일이 코드로 되어 있던것들 말이예요
e-mails in code.
- 라살입니다
- 저거좀 키워봐
Lasalle here.
Turn that up.
세바스찬, 뭘 찾았어?
Sebastian, what do you got?
지금 뉴올리언스의 C구역 담당
헤밀턴 시의원님의
I'm standing outside the offices
of Councilman Hamilton
사무실에 서 있는데요
of District C here
in New Orleans.
의원님은 최근에 도시에서 있었던
He'll be hosting
a press conference today
갱들의 폭력에 대해서 기자회견을
to talk about a recent rash
of gang violence
연다고 하십니다
that's hit the city.
헤밀턴 시의원님은 또한
All in all, Councilman Hamilton
자신을 법과 정의의 후보자로서
is positioning himself
as a law-and-order candidate
1년후에 다가올 시장
선거에 나서고 계십니다
ahead of this year's
mayoral election.
좋아, 꺼버려
Okay, turn it off.
세바스찬이 저희에게
보여주고 싶은게 있답니다
Sebastian wants
to show us something.
문신 잉크에 관해서래요
It's about the tattoo ink.
좋아, 가봐
All right, do it.
난 저 사람을 상대하지
I'll deal with him.
제 살인 사건을 선거 선전용으로
거대하게 부풀려서
I'd appreciate if you'd stop
using my murder investigation
사용하지 말아주셨으면 하는데요
as an excuse to grandstand.
좋아, 이, 이게 내가
잘 이해가 안되는 부분인데
All right, he-here's
what I don't get, okay?
좋아, 당신은 밖에 나가서
이 시를 위해 모든 일을 하고 있기때문에
All right, you are beloved from
Bourbon Street to the swamps
버본 거리부터 가난한 거리까지
'cause you go out of your
way to be of assistance
사랑받고 있는데 말이야...
to this whole
city, including...
내 시의원 상대들을 포함해서 말이지
all of my counterparts
on the council.
하지만 당신과 나는 아직
어울리지를 못한단 말이지
And yet you and I
still can't get along.
뭐, 다른 분들이 의원님보다
성격이 좋을 수도 있죠
Well, maybe they're just nicer than you.
범죄를 덮기 위해 특별 조직이 필요하세요?
마음껏 하시죠
You want a task force to roll up
crime? I'm all for it.
지금 당장 나가서 사람들을 잡아들이자고요
Let's right now get out there
and go arrest people.
대신 두가지 조건이 있습니다
I only have two conditions:
진짜 죄를 저지른 사람만 잡아넣는 것
We arrest them for things
they've actually done,
언론플레이는 하지 말자는 것
and we leave the
cameras behind.
어, 무슨 상관인가, 프라이드?
Uh, what do you care,
Pride?
그냥 쓰레기중 하나가
다른 쓰레기에게 조각난 것 뿐이라고
It was just a gangbanger who
got chopped up by another one.
그는 이름이 있었습니다
He had a name.
켈빈 파크스라는 이름이요
Calvin Parks.
그를 다시 쓰레기라고 부른다면
You call him a gangbanger again,
우리의 문제는
훨씬 악화될겁니다
and our getting along problem
is gonna get a whole lot worse.
FDA 에서
Did you know the FDA
문신 잉크는 관리 안하는거 아세요?
doesn't regulate tattoo ink?
정말 이상한거예요
It's a weird quirk.
화장은 피부 위에
바르는거니까 관리를 하는데
They regulate makeup that's
applied on top of the skin,
잉크는 피부 안으로 들어가니
관리를 안하는거죠
but since the ink goes under
the skin, it's not covered.
- 무슨 소리야?
- 무슨 뜻이냐면 제작사들은
Meaning?
Manufacturers aren't
잉크에 어떤 성분이 들어가 있는지
보고하지 않아도 된다는거죠
required to report
what heavy metals
they use for pigment bases.
그리고... 기본으로 지정되어 있는
잉크의 조합법 자체도 없고요
And... there's no
standard mix for ink.
어떤 잉크는 카디뮴을 포함하고
어떤건 철이나 구리를 포함하죠
Some inks contain cadmium,
others use iron and copper.
그러니까, 그들이
만드는 물품은 마치...
So the end product that they
produce, it's kind of like...
지문같은거네요
Is like a fingerprint.
DNA에 좀 더 가깝지만요
More like DNA,
하지만 제대로 요점을
짚으시네요, 브로디 요원
but you're cooking with gas,
Agent Brody.
아무튼, 제작사의 이름을
일곱으로 줄여보고
Anyway, I narrowed down the
list of suppliers to seven.
그 물품들을 켈빈의 피부 조직에 실험해 본 결과
Then I tested their inks
against Calvin's tissue sample,
타이나티엄-바리움의 잉크를
and there is only one
쓰는건 단 하나밖에 없어요
that uses
that exact barium-
잡지에도 실려있죠
titanium blend.
It is on Magazine.
그리고 이 정보를 드리는 대신
조건이 하나 있어요
And I will gladly share this
with you under one condition.
조건도 있어?
There's a condition?
절 데려가주세요
이 실험실 밖에 나가서
Take me with you.
I got to get out of the lab
그냥 살아있는 것들을 좀 봐야겠어요
and just see something
that's alive.
미래의 문명이
우리가 잉크를 가지고
Got to wonder what future
civilizations are gonna think
찌르고 놀았다는거에 어떻게
생각할지 생각해보셨어요?
about our dabbling
in the ancient arts of ink.
술과 문신은 같이
어울리지 못한다고 하겠지
They'll say drinking and tatting
don't mix.
내 엉덩이에 문신이 박힌
이유가 그거인걸
That's how I ended up
with Big Al on my derriere.
그런거라고
Roll Tide.
있잖아요, 저도 불활성 가스표를
You know,
I thought about getting
여기에 문신으로
넣어보려고 했는데 말이예요...
the noble gas column from
the periodic table, right...
그거 아니면 반지의 제왕에서
나온게 좋을 것 같더라고요
That or something
from Lord of the Rings.
Hmm.
브로디?
Brody?
개인적인거에요
It's private.
- 그림이 문제인가?
- 아니면 장소라던지요
The subject matter?
Or the location?
내 사생활을 침범하지
말아주셨으면 하네요, 고마워요
Don't intimate about my
intimacies, please. Thank you.
제 생각엔... 깨진 하트랑
I'm thinking...
a broken heart.
엉덩이에 섹시한 여자랑
Sexy girl on a mud flap, and...
반지의 제왕에 나온
뭔가를 원하시는것 같군요
something to do with
Lord of the Rings.
NCIS입니다
NCIS.
이거 뭔지 아시겠어요?
Recognize this?
절 모욕하시는군요
저건 제 작품이 아니예요
You're insulting me.
That's not my work.
그럼 이 사람은요?
What about this guy?
마지막으로 보셨을 땐
죽어있었잖아요
When you last saw him,
he was dead.
워, 잠시만요, 죽은 선원에
대해서는 저는 아무것도 몰라요
Whoa, wait, I don't know
anything about a dead sailor.
- 확실하세요?
- 네
You sure about that?
Yeah.
- 이봐요, 이건 뭡니까?
- 이봐요, 이봐요, 이봐요
Hey, what's this?
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
- 뭐하시는겁니까?
- 이런 죄송해요
What are you doing? What are you doing?
Oh, sorry about that.
- 이봐요, 뭐하시는겁니까?
- 걱정마세요
Hey, what are you doing?
Hey, don't worry about it.
세바스찬, 일거리야
Sebastian,
do your thing.
질문이 좀 있습니다만
Got a question
for you.
최근 치과에 다녀오셨습니까?
Had any dental work lately?
- 뭐라고요?
- 신경치료는요?
What?
Root canal?
- 충치는요?
- 교정은요?
Cavities?
Bridge work?
이빨을 빼시거나요?
Extractions?
바리움과 티타니움이예요
그의 잉크가 맞네요
Barium and titanium.
It's his ink.
앙골라에 있는 감옥에서
문신을 교환하는데
Your skill set is gonna
come in handy trading tats
아주 좋은 재능이 될 수 있겠군
for prison hooch in Angola.
좋아요, 보세요, 그 자식이 저한테
문신만 해주면 500불을 주겠다고 했다고요
All right, look. A guy offered
me $500 for a needle and a vial.
- 누가요?
- 돈이랑 이름은 같이 안 딸려온다고요
What guy?
Cash doesn't come with a name.
보세요, 절 보세요
제 이빨도 보세요
Come on, look at me.
Look at my teeth.
제 혀도 보세요
보고 싶으신거 다 보세요
Look at my tongue,
look whatever you need.
저희쪽 몽타쥬 화가에게 의뢰인의 얼굴을
We'll need you to provide
a description of the man
설명해주셨으면 합니다만
to our sketch artist.
몽타쥬 화가요?
Sketch artist? Please.
전 로드 아일랜드
미술학교에 다녔다고요
I went to the
Rhode Island School of Design.
하, 로드 아일랜드 미술 학교라
예술가들이란...
Ha. Rhode Island School
of Design. Artists.
브루스는 이것보다
더 안좋은 것도 봤는걸
Bruce has definitely
seen worse.
한쪽눈이랑 여드름만 가지도고
신원을 조회할 수 있다고
He can get an I.D. with
one eye and a pimple.
안그래, 브루스?
Ain't that right, Bruce?
지금 안면 인식 시스템에
이름을 붙여준거예요?
So, you've nicknamed the
facial recognition system?
그래, 문제 있어?
You bet.
Is that a problem?
- 진짜 이상하시네요
- 몸에 있는
You're weird.
I-I was told
예술 작품에 대해서
물어보라고 들었었는데
that there's some body art
I should ask you about.
이래서 공과 사는
구분하고 싶다고 한거라고요
This is why I prefer
to keep my work
and personal lives separate.
좋아, 헤롤드 워너라는군요
Yes. Harold Werner.
부두에서 일하던 띨빵이요?
Chucklehead
from the wharfs?
어쩐지 빨리 튀더라더니
I thought he scampered
off in a hurry.
주소를 알아내
Get an address.
헤롤드 워너
Harold Werner.
NCIS다, 문열어
NCIS. Open up.
클리어
Clear.
찾았네
We found him.
이해 좀 시켜주세요
분명 작당을 한건 맞을꺼예요
Walk me through this.
We know Harold was in on it,
왜냐하면 잉크를 산 사람은
헤롤드였으니까요
'cause he's the one
who bought the ink.
그리고 자살을 하지 않았다는건
And we know he didn't
kill himself.
그런 식으로 장롱에 박혀 있었으니
스스로 확인이 되고요
Stuffed in a closet
pretty much confirms that.
입은 좀 어떤데?
What's he got going
on in his mouth?
전부 있어요, 32개 전부 다요
Full set. 32 and counting.
그러니까, 헤롤드는
자기 컨테이너에서 살해당한거네
So, Harold gets done
in his own trailer.
자기 스스로 장롱에
들어갔을리가 없으니
Not likely he was
snuck up on in there.
이빨 없는 동료는
The toothless
accomplice.
어디서 찾아야 할까요?
Where we gonna
find him?
켈빈이 찾은 곳에서 말이지
Same place Calvin did.
헤롤드요?
좀 말이 되는 것 같네요
Harold? I suppose that
does make some sense.
왜냐하면 최근 몇달동안
돈이 좀 부족했는데 갑자기 괜찮아졌거든요
'Cause for years he's been
short on money. Last few months
he started
living it up.
그가 같이 일을 하던 사람이나
해군의 물품에 손을 댈 수 잇는 사람의
We're wondering if you could
give us a list of people
he was working closely with,
who might have also had access
목록을 건내주실 수
있으면 좋겠습니다만
to shipments intended
for the Navy.
물론이죠
Of course.
뭐든지 돕겠습니다
모든건 사무실에 있습니다
Anything to help.
It's all in the office.
뭐 하나 말해도 될까요?
Can I say something?
헤롤드가 밀수업자라는걸
그렇게 빨리 납득한거?
Awfully quick to accept
Harold as a smuggler?
그리고 제가 이빨이 빠졌다면
And if I'd lost a tooth...
얼음을 이용해서 고통을 덜었겠죠
I'd use ice
to dull the pain.
저녀석이 3초 내에 튄다에 걸지
I'd say he starts
running in three,
two, one.
- 내가 갈께!
- 제가 갈께요!
I got this.
NCIS다! 멈춰!
NCIS! Stop!
손들어, 손들어!
Hands, hands!
손 들어 보여줘!
Let me see your hands!
이리와
Come here.
자, 한번 볼까?
한번 보자고!
Now, will you look at that?
Look at that.
자식아, 넌 내가 집에 들어가야 하는 횟수만큼
치과에 가봐야겠구나
Son, you need a dentist
like I need to move back home.
그만 저항해
Stop resisting.
그래서 사무실 안에서
부두의 컨테이너의 키를 찾았는데
So, inside the office
we found a key
and the key led us
to the wharf shack.
엄청난 양이 있었어요
The mother lode.
헤로인이군
Heroin.
확실하게 하려고
연구실에 보냈지만
It's being sent
to the lab to confirm,
제 생각에도 헤로인이 맞는 것 같네요
but it'd answer
what was being smuggled.
살인 무기는?
Murder weapon?
다시 말하지만
Again,
연구실에 갔어요
off to the lab.
자 우리는 심문하러 가지
And we're off to interrogation.
정말 따듯하군
Warm today.
에어콘이 정말 기분 좋게
느껴지는군, 안 그래?
Air-conditioning
feels good, doesn't it?
베니에랑 레몬에이드만 있으면
천국에 있는 기분일텐데 말이죠
All I need now is a beignet
and some lemonade,
and I'd be in heaven.
아스피린이 고통을 좀 덜어주던?
Aspirin help
your toothache?
내가 더 아프게 만들었다면
일단 사과부터 하지
My apologies
if I made it worse.
그래서, 켈빈 파크스 병장이
So, Petty Officer
Calvin Parks
네가 헤로인을 밀수하는걸 발견했지
discovered you were
smuggling heroin.
그리고 넌 그녀석이 상관에게
보고하지 않도록 그를
You had him killed him to
make sure he didn't report
죽여버려야만 했던거야
what he knew
up his chain of command.
갱 문신은...
Gang tattoo was...
우릴 헷갈리게 하는데
정말 큰 역활을 했지
a clever way to throw us off.
내가 정말 궁금한건
What's bothering me
네 직업 기록이야
is your employment file.
뉴올리언스에는 2년밖에 없었다고 하더군
Says you've only been in
New Orleans for two years.
파크스 병장이 갱과 연관이
있었다는건 넌 몰랐지, 그렇지?
You didn't know he had a past
with the gangs, did you?
아뇨
No.
그럼, 누가 켈빈의 팔에
문신을 넣으라고 가르쳐줬지?
So, who told
you to put
the tattoo on Calvin's arm?
사실을 말하면 풀어주지
Truth will set you free.
대체 뭐하는 겁니까?
What the hell is she doing?
새로운 문신을 주는거지
네 감옥 동료들에게
Giving you a new tattoo.
Letting the inmates
니가 그들이 찾는 새로운
타겟이라고 말해줄 문신 말이야
in the pen know you're
the target they're looking for.
켈빈에게 그 문신을 놓아서
You put that tat on Calvin,
그 총격 사건이 일어나게 했으니
caused that little
shooting spree.
델타 크루 녀석들이나
Like to think the Delta Crew
113 녀석들이 널 잡고
싶어서 안달을 하겠군
and the 1-1-3s would like
a little piece of you.
제가 아는걸 말하게 되면
갱은 제가 걱정해야할 마지막 문제가 될 겁니다
If I say what I know, gangs
are the least of my worries.
다 끝나면 전화해
Call me when he's processed.
넌 미 해군 선원을 죽인 죄로
You're going to prison
for murdering
감옥에 가는거야
a United States Navy sailor.
즐겁게 살아봐, 친구
Enjoy the party, my friend.
안녕하세요, 헤밀턴씨
Afternoon, Hamilton.
아, 안녕하세요, 드웨인씨
Oh, afternoon,
Dwayne. Say, uh,
범인을 잡았다고 하시더군요
정말 잘하셨습니다
I hear congratulations are in
order. You got your man. Good.
이게 제가 좀 걸리는 부분인데
Here's what I'm chewing on:
누가 그녀석 구역에서 항구를 가지고 있을까?
Who's got the port
in his district?
세관이 밀수로 눈을 돌리게 함으로서
Who'd get a taste from
누가 가장 이득을 볼까?
getting customs to look the
other way on a smuggling ring?
누가 특수부대를 만들려고
Who'd incite a gang war
갱 전쟁을 시작했을까?
to justify a task force?
그리고 켈빈의 어린 실수를
And who would have known enough
누가 그렇게 잘 알아서
about Calvin's
youthful indiscretions
문신을 하라고 조언을 해 줬을까?
to have suggested a tattoo?
엄청난 가설이군요, 드웨인
That's quite a theory, Dwayne.
그걸 증명할만한 증거는 있습니까?
You got any proof
to back that up?
아직은 없죠
Not yet.
하지만 제가 찾아낼 거라는건 아시지않습니까
But you know I will.
제 도시에서 또 봅시다
See you around my city.
당신의 도시요?
Your city?
잊지 마시라고요
Don't you ever forget it.
첫번째 술은 제가 쏠께요
First round is on me.
뭘 축하하는거지?
What are we celebrating?
누군가 새로운 아파트가 생겼다네요
Someone has a new apartment.
라살의 친구가 가진
작은 게스트 하우스인데
Adorable little guest house
owned by a friend of Lasalle's.
정원도 있어요
It's got a garden,
렌트도 싸고, 그리고...
rent's pretty cheap, and, uh,
마디 그라스 길에 있다고요
it's on the Mardi Gras route.
그리고 거기에 살게 됨으로서...
Which defines you as...
제가 여기 와서 정말
흥분된다고 말해주죠
Thrilled to be here.
이사하는 사람들이예요
잠시만요, 여보세요?
Movers. Excuse me. Hello?
마디 그라스 길에 있는 게스트 하우스라?
Guest house with a garden
on the Mardi Gras route?
브로디한테 라살의 친구가
누군지 언제 말해줄 계획이야?
When are you gonna tell Brody
who Lasalle's friend is?
렌트 가격을 올려야 할 때죠
When I have to raise the rent.
있죠, 마지막 렌트했던 두 사람들은
정말 골칫덩어리여서
You know, my last two tenants
re a pain in my ass, so
가족에게 렌트하는것도 좋을것 같아요
it'll be nice to rent it to family.
Yeah.
잠시만 자리좀 비우지
Excuse me a moment.
물론이죠, 드웨인
Sure thing, Dwayne.
고마워 드웨인
Thank you, Dwayne.
생각도 하지마
Think nothing of it.
만약 녀석이 다시 갱에
들어갔다고 했다면, 아마 난 자살했을꺼야
Would've killed me knowing he'd
wanted back in with them gangs.
아, 갱에 들어가고
싶어하긴 했었지, 내꺼에 말이야
Oh, he wanted to
join a gang. Mine.
켈빈은 사건을 맡고 있었어
그리고 정말 잘했지
Calvin was working a
case. And he was good.
무슨 일이 일어나는지 알기 위해서는
많은 생각을 했어야 했었겠지
Took a lot of thinking to
figure out what was going on.
그리고 만약 켈빈이 내 부하였다면...
And if he was mine--
많은 부분에서, 이미 내 부하였지만...
in many ways, he was--
난 정말 자랑스러웠을꺼야
I'd be awfully proud.
너, 음...
You, uh...
첫번째 곡 같이 할래?
want to sit in
on the first song?
영광이지
Be my honor.
좋아 "마디 그라스로 가라"야
All right.
"Go to the Mardi Gras."
B-플랫으로
B-flat.
잘한다, 프라이드!
솵 솵Go, Pride!
우리 대장도 좀 하시지?
King can play, can't he?
믿을 수가 없네
I can't believe him.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man